<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Portfolio</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/</id><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Coloring Page Generators</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/coloring-page-generators.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2020-05-01:/portfolio/coloring-page-generators.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A crossover between creative coding and drawing, two of my favourite things to do. 
These coloring page generators combine drawings of parts of the image in a unique, random way to generate a new coloring page every time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you like space, &lt;a href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/spacestation"&gt;this space station generator&lt;/a&gt; is your thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A crossover between creative coding and drawing, two of my favourite things to do. 
These coloring page generators combine drawings of parts of the image in a unique, random way to generate a new coloring page every time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you like space, &lt;a href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/spacestation"&gt;this space station generator&lt;/a&gt; is your thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or if you're into an underground adventure, check out &lt;a href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/caves-and-tunnels"&gt;this caves and tunnels generator&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="other"></category></entry><entry><title>Infographic on the brewing process</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/infographic-on-the-brewing-process.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2020-04-08:/portfolio/infographic-on-the-brewing-process.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For my brother who has founded his own brewery.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Wishing someone a happy birthday</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/wishing-someone-a-happy-birthday.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2020-04-03:/portfolio/wishing-someone-a-happy-birthday.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And having to run because I'm always late.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Django Day Copenhagen 2020</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/django-day-copenhagen-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2020-04-01:/portfolio/django-day-copenhagen-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was my first ever assignment and it went so well I want to do more of them. 
I learned a lot during such a short period. I got better at digitizing my work and coloring svgs. 
There was a lot of communication back and forth via Email, but Django …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was my first ever assignment and it went so well I want to do more of them. 
I learned a lot during such a short period. I got better at digitizing my work and coloring svgs. 
There was a lot of communication back and forth via Email, but Django Denmark was such a lovely organization to work together with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the lovely collaboration, for your inspiration and your friendly feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="other"></category></entry><entry><title>Putting thoughts into words</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/putting-thoughts-into-words.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2020-03-25:/portfolio/putting-thoughts-into-words.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;is hard and frustrating at times...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Pressekonferenz des Bundesrates</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/pressekonferenz-des-bundesrates.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2020-03-16:/portfolio/pressekonferenz-des-bundesrates.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;zur Ausrufung der ausserordentliche Lage in der Schweiz wegen dem Corona Virus&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Thought Overload</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/thought-overload.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-10-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-10-26:/portfolio/thought-overload.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Too many thoughts in my head...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Advanced, free, open-source application performance monitoring for your Python web apps</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/advanced-free-open-source-application-performance-monitoring-for-your-python-web-apps.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Emanuil Tolev</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-12:/portfolio/advanced-free-open-source-application-performance-monitoring-for-your-python-web-apps.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this talk and technical demo we’re going to walk through a minimal example Django web app, simulate traffic of varied intensity, and monitor the entire system as well as peek deeper in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 3am. Your phone rings with a special tone - the systems propping up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this talk and technical demo we’re going to walk through a minimal example Django web app, simulate traffic of varied intensity, and monitor the entire system as well as peek deeper in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 3am. Your phone rings with a special tone - the systems propping up your employer’s or client’s website are down. You open your eyes and groan, fumbling for your laptop. You’re used to the system’s worst problems, you have an idea what it might be. It’s slow going while you manually check if every component is working. You go back to bed in an hour, having written up a few of the most important details and brought the website back up. Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, at 6am you get another call. You sigh and fix it. Then another at 7am, and at 11am. A few days later the outages repeat. What is going on?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are types of problems that can’t be solved purely through experience and knowledge of a system. You need deeper monitoring data than “% CPU” and “RAM free” to resolve them. Worse still, there are multiple components involved with failures in one masking a true underlying cause in another, like a slow loading page masking a slow database, which in turn makes you wonder what queries it’s really answering. In this talk we’re going to have a look at how you can monitor small to medium projects to really understand deeper problems at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will pick specific solutions from various vendors as well as open source for different parts of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Apathy and Arsenic: a Victorian Era lesson on fighting the surveillance state</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/apathy-and-arsenic-a-victorian-era-lesson-on-fighting-the-surveillance-state.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Lilly Ryan</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-12:/portfolio/apathy-and-arsenic-a-victorian-era-lesson-on-fighting-the-surveillance-state.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does expensive Victorian era wallpaper have in common with a Cambridge Analytica Facebook quiz?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is the GDPR like a trip to a seaside resort?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could a cryptoparty have anything to do with a rare book in a library in Michigan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly Ryan - historian, privacy advocate, and penetration …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does expensive Victorian era wallpaper have in common with a Cambridge Analytica Facebook quiz?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is the GDPR like a trip to a seaside resort?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could a cryptoparty have anything to do with a rare book in a library in Michigan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly Ryan - historian, privacy advocate, and penetration tester - walks you through a two hundred year old method for fighting the surveillance state, based on the advocacy led by 19th century scientists to abolish the domestic use of arsenic. You will learn about the tireless efforts used by anti-arsenic activists to change the public perception of arsenic, Cory Doctorow’s theory of Peak Indifference, the lives ruined by data breaches, and how to sustain the recent public shift from “I have nothing to hide” to “I value my privacy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will offer tips for developers, security professionals, and other interested folks on how to help everyday people have more power over their own information and how to sustain hope for the future when we’ve been aware of the solutions for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come along and take in stories of murder, mismanagement, and mendacity, and learn how to keep up the fight against mass surveillance now that the tide is turning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Building a Django Community in Africa</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/building-a-django-community-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Abigail Mesrenyame Dogbe &amp; Noah Alorwu</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-12:/portfolio/building-a-django-community-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The fast spread of Django in Africa through some initiatives such as Django Girls and Python Conferences has gained popularity especially in the West of Africa. Pushing the agenda of creating an active community will go a long way to promote the use of Django and strengthen the relationship between …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The fast spread of Django in Africa through some initiatives such as Django Girls and Python Conferences has gained popularity especially in the West of Africa. Pushing the agenda of creating an active community will go a long way to promote the use of Django and strengthen the relationship between Django developers in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Building plugin ecosystems with Django</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/building-plugin-ecosystems-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Raphael Michel</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-12:/portfolio/building-plugin-ecosystems-with-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The power of some popular web applications like WordPress comes from a flexible plugin system. This talk will show how to implement such plugin architectures for Django applications including real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably common sense by now that modular architectures win over monolithic architectures in a number of ways …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The power of some popular web applications like WordPress comes from a flexible plugin system. This talk will show how to implement such plugin architectures for Django applications including real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably common sense by now that modular architectures win over monolithic architectures in a number of ways. Django gives us reusable apps, but just because they are reusable doesn’t mean they automatically integrate nicely with each other and a Python programmer is still required to glue them together. In this talk I will show how to build a rich Django application that provides a well-defined plugin API. The API will allow plugins to seamlessly integrate with the main application. The talk will show various patterns around URL routing, Django‘s signal system and the use of setuptools to provide auto-detection of installed plugins. Installing a plugin should not be much more complicated than a simple pip install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explained architecture has been in use for some years in the pretix open source project and made it possible to us to grow a rich plugin ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Identity and nothingness in Python and Django</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/identity-and-nothingness-in-python-and-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daniele Procida</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-12:/portfolio/identity-and-nothingness-in-python-and-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s something rich, beautiful and mysterious in the several kinds of nothingness and identity that we encounter as Python/Django programmers. Understanding the connections they make with ontology, epistemology and metaphysics adds another dimension to the joy of programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Django programmers, we’re blessed - we have several kinds …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s something rich, beautiful and mysterious in the several kinds of nothingness and identity that we encounter as Python/Django programmers. Understanding the connections they make with ontology, epistemology and metaphysics adds another dimension to the joy of programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Django programmers, we’re blessed - we have several kinds of nothingness and identity at our fingertips. There’s something rich, beautiful and mysterious in them, and in their variety and relation. For the programmer, the discovery of them is an opening into Python’s power and expressiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the same richness and mystery that logicians and philosophers have discovered in them: entire schools of thought are founded on various approaches to nothingness. Programmers are in fact working with key ideas that are also crucially important to ontology, epistemology and metaphysics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the pioneers of boolean electronics who adopted the NAND gate as the basic building block of logical circuits to thinkers like Sartre and Kant, nothing repeatedly turns out to be at the heart of everything. And the Python programmer who gets a surprise when checking for the identity of a variable is in fact running into the same problems that Heraclitus was aware of, 25 centuries before Guido van Rossum was even born. We’re in good company, in other words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothingness and identity and the way we use them in Python and Django are related to phenomenology, utopia, politics, theories of agency and much, much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing about these connections might not make anyone a better programmer, but it can add another dimension to their understanding of the discipline, and add to the richness and beauty of their world, making the joy of programming even deeper.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Maps with GeoDjango, PostGIS and Leaflet</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/maps-with-geodjango-postgis-and-leaflet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Paolo Melchiorre</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-12:/portfolio/maps-with-geodjango-postgis-and-leaflet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will see how we have integrated a map into a web project already in production using GeoDjango, PostGIS and Leaflet and we will perform a demonstration of integration of a map from scratch into a Django project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A map allows users to view and search for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will see how we have integrated a map into a web project already in production using GeoDjango, PostGIS and Leaflet and we will perform a demonstration of integration of a map from scratch into a Django project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A map allows users to view and search for data in a spatial way and it is common to add one to their web project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will see how we have integrated a map into a web project already in production using GeoDjango, PostGIS and Leaflet and we will perform a demonstration of integration of a map from scratch into a Django project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GeoDjango is a module included in Django that transforms it into a world-class geographic Web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PostGIS is an extension of the PostgreSQL database that adds support for geographic objects allowing you to perform spatial queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaflet is the leading open source JavaScript library for interactive web maps optimized for mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Docs or it didn't happen! (with Q&amp;A)</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/docs-or-it-didnt-happen-with-qa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Mikey Ariel</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-11:/portfolio/docs-or-it-didnt-happen-with-qa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever skimmed through a README, tried to follow a quickstart tutorial, attempted to decipher an error message, or typed ‘–help’ in your console? Congratulations – you have encountered documentation! Long gone are the days of massive books with never-ending stories about your software. Today’s users are smarter and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever skimmed through a README, tried to follow a quickstart tutorial, attempted to decipher an error message, or typed ‘–help’ in your console? Congratulations – you have encountered documentation! Long gone are the days of massive books with never-ending stories about your software. Today’s users are smarter and less patient, which means that we no longer need to document all the things, as long as what we do document is clear, concise, helpful, and accessible. And that’s where the real work starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation requires some attitude adjustment, since prose doesn’t neatly compile into binaries as code does. But Don’t Panic™! No matter what your role is in the community, you can apply a few key principles from the technical writing world to make your project more docs-friendly, and therefore more user- and contributor-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk covers strategies, best practices, and pro tips for rethinking how we create and curate documentation. This special edition will include Django-specific examples and use-cases as well as a special Q&amp;amp;A session, where we will try to address some of the community’s top concerns and ideas about the Django docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special edition: Send me questions before the talk, and I will try to answer them on stage. If you have a twitter account send your question here. Otherwise, you can email me at docs@docsideofthemoon.com. Don’t be shy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Does this run in linear time? A case for algorithmics</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/does-this-run-in-linear-time-a-case-for-algorithmics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Iulia Avram</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-11:/portfolio/does-this-run-in-linear-time-a-case-for-algorithmics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Algorithms are fun to learn and their usefulness goes beyond getting that good grade or acing a coding interview. This talk aims to showcase some the hidden benefits of keeping your algorithmic skills sharp, as well as the speaker’s personal recommendations in keeping up the good work without feeling …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Algorithms are fun to learn and their usefulness goes beyond getting that good grade or acing a coding interview. This talk aims to showcase some the hidden benefits of keeping your algorithmic skills sharp, as well as the speaker’s personal recommendations in keeping up the good work without feeling like studying for an exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many sorting methods can you name out of your head? What is greedy? If these terms sound familiar, you’ve probably heard of algorithmics. For the everyday developer, algorithms are either the scare of all the technical interviews, or that one course you took in university which they vaguely remember. It seems that if you’re not working for one of the big companies, you will never use them. So you might ask yourself: Why do I need to know about linear time when the libraries I’m using already optimise for this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you might not implement binary search in that new feature you’re working on, or use dynamic programming, diving a bit deeper into this world could prove useful in training your mind to see patterns you might have a harder time seeing otherwise, or to write code that is better optimised and will give the end users a better experience. I am going to try to dispel some of the myths surrounding the study of algorithms and competitive programming, and argue that sharpening this skill is something that benefits us, as software developers, outside of passing technical tests.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Here Come The Robots - Django and Machine Learning</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/here-come-the-robots-django-and-machine-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tom Dyson</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-11:/portfolio/here-come-the-robots-django-and-machine-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A practical, hands-on guide to using machine learning in your Django projects, including a live demo of four applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning is probably the most important development in our industry (and possibly our civilisation!). Previously restricted to math geniuses with access to supercomputers and massive data centres, machine learning tools …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A practical, hands-on guide to using machine learning in your Django projects, including a live demo of four applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning is probably the most important development in our industry (and possibly our civilisation!). Previously restricted to math geniuses with access to supercomputers and massive data centres, machine learning tools are increasingly available as web services which are easily consumed from more traditional web applications. Python has become the lingua franca of machine learning, so Django developers are well placed to take advantage of the next wave of application development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I’ll outline the various machine learning platforms and provide a set of practical examples that demonstrate how Django developers can start taking advantage of artificial intelligence in their own applications. These will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image recognition - using Microsoft Azure Vision to automatically caption and label the images your users upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entity analysis - using the Google Cloud Natural Language API to tag news articles with people, locations and events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictions - using Amazon Machine Learning to build a ‘you may also like’ feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sentiment analysis - using IBM Watson to understand the tone of comments submitted to your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Reduce, Reuse, Recycle - Persisting WebSocket connections with SharedWorkers</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/reduce-reuse-recycle-persisting-websocket-connections-with-sharedworkers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Bassett</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-11:/portfolio/reduce-reuse-recycle-persisting-websocket-connections-with-sharedworkers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When using WebSockets to communicate between your server and the client every new browser context–tab, window, iframe, and so on–is likely to create another WebSocket connection. All these open connections can quickly take a toll on your server resources, or if you’re using a PaaS which charges …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When using WebSockets to communicate between your server and the client every new browser context–tab, window, iframe, and so on–is likely to create another WebSocket connection. All these open connections can quickly take a toll on your server resources, or if you’re using a PaaS which charges for each connection, it could quickly add up to a big bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll look at how you can use SharedWorkers to create a single persistent WebSocket which can be used by every browser context to communicate with your Django Channels WebSocket server&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Serverless Django with Zappa</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/serverless-django-with-zappa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Neal Todd</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-11:/portfolio/serverless-django-with-zappa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exploration of how Serverless can be used to run your Django applications with the pros and cons of doing so. The focus is on AWS Lambda using Zappa for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, Serverless has become an increasingly popular option for serving applications, going beyond even …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exploration of how Serverless can be used to run your Django applications with the pros and cons of doing so. The focus is on AWS Lambda using Zappa for deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, Serverless has become an increasingly popular option for serving applications, going beyond even containerisation in its promise of minimal DevOps overheads and reduced operational costs - unburdening developers to focus on the applications themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often serverless is used in conjunction with microservices as part of a larger application stack. But how effective is it for running your entire Django application as an alternative to the traditional ‘always-on’ model for a website? This talk explores the pros and cons of running your own personal/experimental Django projects and the challenges of using it in a full production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be exploring this with a concrete example based on AWS Lambda and associated services, Zappa for deployment and Wagtail as the Django application to give a Serverless Content Mangement System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk is accompanied by online documentation so that attendees can run their own Serverless CMS or their own application with little or no running costs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Simple visual regression testing</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/simple-visual-regression-testing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Zelma Gist</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-11:/portfolio/simple-visual-regression-testing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visual regression testing is an afterthought to many developers working on lean development teams. We will go over how to create automated visual tests that are both scalable and simple to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us will agree that testing CSS changes is important…in theory. But when you have limited …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visual regression testing is an afterthought to many developers working on lean development teams. We will go over how to create automated visual tests that are both scalable and simple to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us will agree that testing CSS changes is important…in theory. But when you have limited development time and no QA resources, how do you ensure that pages look as expected after CSS changes? Instead of constantly having to click around we can programmatically detect UI changes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will start with how to set up your existing test environment with automated visual tests using Python and Selenium. Then we will discuss a few pit falls that I ran into when implementing visual regression testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will be expected to have a general understanding about how test cases are set up in Django&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Django and Web Security Headers</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/django-and-web-security-headers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Adam Johnson</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-10:/portfolio/django-and-web-security-headers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Web browsers support several HTTP headers to opt in to extra security features. I’ll explain then and show you how to get an A+ rating for these with the free checker SecurityHeaders.com, using built-in features and a few third-party packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web browser is an evolving environment, but …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Web browsers support several HTTP headers to opt in to extra security features. I’ll explain then and show you how to get an A+ rating for these with the free checker SecurityHeaders.com, using built-in features and a few third-party packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web browser is an evolving environment, but with massive backwards compatibility. Because of this, a lot of its security features are opt-in and incremental through headers such as Content-Security-Policy and Feature-Policy. I’ll walk through and explain the main headers recommended by Scott Helme’s SecurityHeaders.com , and how you can get your site to an A+ score, with a mix of built-in features and third party packages for the more cutting edge headers. Also I’ll briefly show some free and paid tools that can aid with deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Feeding the Pony: Contributing back to Django &amp; How to make that work for you</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/feeding-the-pony-contributing-back-to-django-how-to-make-that-work-for-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Carlton Gibson</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-10:/portfolio/feeding-the-pony-contributing-back-to-django-how-to-make-that-work-for-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Django’s life-blood is its contributors. This talk is about how we enable more contributors from across the community, how they (You!) can get involved, and how you can make sure that it helps your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django looks like it’s doing just fine: it’s a popular framework in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Django’s life-blood is its contributors. This talk is about how we enable more contributors from across the community, how they (You!) can get involved, and how you can make sure that it helps your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django looks like it’s doing just fine: it’s a popular framework in a popular language. We have major releases every six months. We have Django Girls, a Foundation (and Fellows), super conferences in glamorous locations, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the code is old and there’s only the smallest number of people that regularly contribute. We need more. We need you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, as good as we are elsewhere as a community, the group of contributors isn’t as diverse as the community at large: there are clearly barriers to entry here. We’re trying to change that, and we want to invite you to come and join-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to open source is great fun, it’s a great learning opportunity, and it can really help your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to tell you how to get involved, and how to get support in that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly I’m going to tell you how to avoid the pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are qualified to contribute. More than that, your contribution is the future of Django. Come code!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Logging Rethought 2: The Actions of Frank Taylor Jr.</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/logging-rethought-2-the-actions-of-frank-taylor-jr.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Markus Holtermann</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-10:/portfolio/logging-rethought-2-the-actions-of-frank-taylor-jr.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We build services, potentially used by hundreds, thousands or even millions of people. And despite all the testing we do, some operations and interactions with these services will not work out the way we expect or hope. Wouldn’t it be great to be able to reconstruct what led to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We build services, potentially used by hundreds, thousands or even millions of people. And despite all the testing we do, some operations and interactions with these services will not work out the way we expect or hope. Wouldn’t it be great to be able to reconstruct what led to a problem? And then analyze if the same problem occurred at other times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I want to look at structured logging. What are the benefits of it over plain-text logging? How can it be used effectively?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logging, by itself, can help to trace bugs. Structured logging adds additional, post-logging capabilities when used correctly. Because log events are structured data, they can be analyzed much more efficiently and effectively than plain text log messages. Furthermore, one can even build graphs and diagrams to visualize what’s happening in a service nicely.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Making your life (h)APIer with Django</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/making-your-life-hapier-with-django.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Emma Delescolle</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-10:/portfolio/making-your-life-hapier-with-django.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In today’s web, creating API’s has become a big part of web-development. Django and Django REST Framework make our lives easy :-) But let’s take it a notch further with DRF-Schema-Adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to building API’s with Django, Django REST Framework has become the go-to solution …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In today’s web, creating API’s has become a big part of web-development. Django and Django REST Framework make our lives easy :-) But let’s take it a notch further with DRF-Schema-Adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to building API’s with Django, Django REST Framework has become the go-to solution. It is a great tool that integrates seamlessly with Django and it’s ORM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately when building a medium-to-large API, DRF leads to a lot of very similar and somewhat repetitive code in building your ViewSet, Serializer, Pagination or Filter classes. In the long-run, all this code also has to be maintained!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where DRF-Schema-Adapter can make your life easier and happier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll go over the basics of building an API with DRF versus using DRF-Schema-Adapter and how it will help shrink your codebase.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Pushing the ORM to its limits</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/pushing-the-orm-to-its-limits.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sigurd Ljødal</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2019-04-10:/portfolio/pushing-the-orm-to-its-limits.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can do a lot more with the Django ORM than you might think, and when something isn’t possible using the existing primitives, you can easily add your own. In this talk you will learn about both advanced features of the ORM and how to run your own SQL …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can do a lot more with the Django ORM than you might think, and when something isn’t possible using the existing primitives, you can easily add your own. In this talk you will learn about both advanced features of the ORM and how to run your own SQL queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django’s ORM makes it super simple to run quick queries against your database, but it can do a lot more for you than you might think. Need to get some statistics on a monthly-basis? Easy, just annotate your queryset with year and month using ExtractYear and ExtractMonth, and you can use .values() to get the data aggregated by month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you find yourself in need of something that is not already covered by the existing ORM functions, you will often be able to create it yourself. Have you modelled your data with separate date and time fields, but need to compare this to a datetime field? You can make a custom expression in Django for combining the date and time into a datetime in the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with Django 1.11, you can easily make subqueries using the Django ORM. In Django 2.0 we got support for window functions. Django 2.1 exposes additional functions that are available in many databases, and version 2.2 will introduce support for custom constraints and extends the primitives for custom indexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also easy to drop down to writing raw SQL if you need to. It is probably not something you need to do every day, but it’s good to know that the option is there, and know how and when to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Fernwehfestival (Bern) 2018</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/fernwehfestival-bern-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-10-28:/portfolio/fernwehfestival-bern-2018.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every year in autumn there is the Globetrotter Fernwehfestival in Bern. 
I visited in 2018 and spent the afternoon in one of the auditoria sketchnoting. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Neurodiversity rainbow</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/neurodiversity-rainbow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-10-03:/portfolio/neurodiversity-rainbow.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Digital drawing experiment&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Sensory Overload Strategy</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/sensory-overload-strategy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-09-23:/portfolio/sensory-overload-strategy.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Protecting myself from too much noise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Scotland 2018</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/scotland-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-09-16:/portfolio/scotland-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Travel without flying is our favorite way. 
One could be surprised how far you can get in just 24 hours. 
We traveled all the way to Glasgow and after staying there for a bit continued our tour around Scotland. 
We used trains, ferries and busses, visited the Isle of skye …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Travel without flying is our favorite way. 
One could be surprised how far you can get in just 24 hours. 
We traveled all the way to Glasgow and after staying there for a bit continued our tour around Scotland. 
We used trains, ferries and busses, visited the Isle of skye and had a river walk in Inverness, before starting our return journey from edinburgh. 
We took the Ferry from Newcastle to Amsterdam and the ICE back to Switzerland. 
We enjoyed this trip very much and no, it didn't even rain that often!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Visiting the trasportation museum in Lucern</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/visiting-the-trasportation-museum-in-lucern.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-09-08:/portfolio/visiting-the-trasportation-museum-in-lucern.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Recipe (2)</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/recipe-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-07-16:/portfolio/recipe-2.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For delicious flatbread.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Drawing faces</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/drawing-faces.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-07-12:/portfolio/drawing-faces.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Because you can never have enough training.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Recipe (1)</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/recipe-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-06-27:/portfolio/recipe-1.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For delicious chocolate chip cookies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>One of those days</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/one-of-those-days.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-06-20:/portfolio/one-of-those-days.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where you wish you'd just stayed in bed&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Lithium: Trends im Digitalen Kundenerlebnis</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/lithium-trends-im-digitalen-kundenerlebnis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Claudius Henrichs &amp; Rahul Hari</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-06-19:/portfolio/lithium-trends-im-digitalen-kundenerlebnis.html</id><content type="html"></content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Cat on the balcony</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/cat-on-the-balcony.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-06-09:/portfolio/cat-on-the-balcony.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our cat was scaring birds on the balcony today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Food from our balcony</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/food-from-our-balcony.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-06-08:/portfolio/food-from-our-balcony.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;tasting delicious.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Icecream</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/icecream.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-06-01:/portfolio/icecream.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is always a good day for eating icecream.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Space</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/space.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-29:/portfolio/space.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Drawing spaceships is fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Happy Birthday (first Version)</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/happy-birthday-first-version.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-25:/portfolio/happy-birthday-first-version.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wishing a happy birthday. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Growing old gracefully: on being a career programmer</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/growing-old-gracefully-on-being-a-career-programmer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Carlton Gibson</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-24:/portfolio/growing-old-gracefully-on-being-a-career-programmer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Software development is often seen as a young person's game. But what if, as you get older, you want to keep at the keyboard? Thoughts from a (now) veteran developer on building your career in software development for the long-haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a community talk. My favourite topics from DjangoConEU …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Software development is often seen as a young person's game. But what if, as you get older, you want to keep at the keyboard? Thoughts from a (now) veteran developer on building your career in software development for the long-haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a community talk. My favourite topics from DjangoConEU 2017 were the non-technical talks. The most interesting (on-topic) conversations I had were about the non-programming aspects of working in software. I wanted to give a talk on that line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prima facie&lt;/em&gt; I'm not the best place person to talk about diversity (white, male, etc), but, having been freelance since 2006, with four young children, and now slightly greying hair, I am in a position to talk about how to build a career in software development for the long-haul. Hiring in tech is massively ageist. I want to discuss strategies to handle that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My target audience is individual programmers (whether freelance or employed) as well as software managers, looking to build &lt;strong&gt;and retain&lt;/strong&gt; a team. (The message for managers is simply that they need to facilitate their employees' careers. This seems obvious but it &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; worth bringing out.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core point of my talk is around the idea that a career is very much a marathon rather than a sprint, and that it needs to be approached in that spirit. (Again, this may seem obvious but it &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; worth bringing out.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects of this. The one is &lt;strong&gt;pace&lt;/strong&gt;. That to work on software day-in, day-out for 10, 20, 30, 40 years (or more) we need to pace ourselves, to manage our reserves, and to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other is that there is noting to be scared of. That expertise which now may seem intimidating is, yes, available to us too. That with 5, 10, 15 years of continued effort we too (yes, us) can be as experienced as whomever, in the speciality we choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bring this out with three points. That we need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be disciplined&lt;/strong&gt;: The key point is to keep going. We each need to find patterns that work for us and develop them into habits that we build into a routine. The great thing is it doesn't have to be 100 hour weeks. As long as we keep doing it, whatever we do builds up over time. Despite the impression to the contrary, time is on our side. Which leads to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be prolific&lt;/strong&gt;: Do lots, and put it out there. This one seems scary. "I'll never do as much as ..." — but it's an illusion. Do one thing. Put that out there. Do something else. Repeat. Again, the work builds up over time, and (seemingly) all of a sudden, you're in a position of being the expert. Finally...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be social&lt;/strong&gt;: And I don't necessarily mean Facebook (unless Facebook is your thing). In whatever environment or medium suits you get out there meet people. (Stretch your comfort zones a bit here.) Share what you've done. Relish in what others have done. Be part of the community. Help build the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three of these are essential. As you get older — all the more as you get older — they allow you to build a sustainable career writing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tale is brought out with stories on finding work, and on choosing clients, and employers, financial planning and job security, on family and free-time, and on the importance self-care. It's part inspiration, part battle-plan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Accessibility Matters: Creating a Better Web</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Lindsey Dragun</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-23:/portfolio/accessibility-matters-creating-a-better-web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is an afterthought to many, but to those with issues navigating the web it's very important. We will go over examples of accessibility on the web, short and long term solutions, and talk about why accessibility matters to a variety of users. The audience should leave with the ability …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is an afterthought to many, but to those with issues navigating the web it's very important. We will go over examples of accessibility on the web, short and long term solutions, and talk about why accessibility matters to a variety of users. The audience should leave with the ability to spot some accessibility issues and the knowledge of how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is a huge topic that is often acknowledged as important...by the people who already care about it. This talk is meant to help the entire audience start thinking about accessibility and realize how easy it is to at least put some accessibility into a site (or avoid adding blatantly inaccessible content).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten to fifteen percent of the EU has a disability, according to the EU Labour Force Survey, which is a large potential audience for any site. There are various laws that factor into the amount of web accessibility a country must have, and the consequences a business can face because of that. Accessible web development also tends to lead to better UX and a happier user base. And, another plus: It will save devs time and frustration when they’re working with the code, since good HTML is enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk will start with a broad introduction to accessibility, how to break different concerns down into categories for consideration, and touch on some laws around web accessibility. The second part will go through examples of good and bad accessibility and what to look out for, as well as ways to improve accessibility (including "easy wins" that they could implement quickly to drastically improve their sites). The final section will include resources for finding accessibility standards and also browser extensions and the like for people to check on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience will be expected to have working knowledge of the internet, webpages, and using webpages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Making smarter queries with advanced ORM resources</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/making-smarter-queries-with-advanced-orm-resources.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Mariana Bedran Lesche</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-23:/portfolio/making-smarter-queries-with-advanced-orm-resources.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Django ORM has lots of resources for making complex database queries and the documentation brings good examples on how to apply each one of them, but understanding how to orchestrate all of those resources on real-life projects may not be so simple. My goal with this talk is to show …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Django ORM has lots of resources for making complex database queries and the documentation brings good examples on how to apply each one of them, but understanding how to orchestrate all of those resources on real-life projects may not be so simple. My goal with this talk is to show through examples how to combine some of the QuerySet Methods, Query Expressions and other optimization techniques to make the most of DB resources when processing information inside the code is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we start modelling an application, we don’t always know how it’s models will evolve and it may be even more difficult to foresee their behaviour when big amounts of data are stored in their respective tables. With tables getting bigger through the project’s life apparently harmless operations may become impossible to make. Thankfully, databases are already prepared for dealing with large amounts of data and resource consuming operations and Django’s ORM provides solutions for most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this talk I’m going to build an example Django project, populate it’s tables with big enough datasets and formulate complex questions to demand the most on the ORM’s possibilities. For each question I’m writing at least one solution using the resources described in the QueryExpressions section of Django’s Docs to then analyse the SQL generated by it and the pros and cons between operational costs and code complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following topics will be covered:
* Using F() expressions for filtering, ordering and annotate operations
* Using Max, Min, Avg with annotations
* Compare Subquery expressions to queryset equivalents
* Present the new Window functions for partitioned operations
* Using Union queries&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Node Red Showcase</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/node-red-showcase.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Cello</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-22:/portfolio/node-red-showcase.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is a programming tool for wiring together hardware devices, APIs and online services in new and interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides a browser-based editor that makes it easy to wire together flows using the wide range of nodes in the palette that can be deployed to its runtime in a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is a programming tool for wiring together hardware devices, APIs and online services in new and interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides a browser-based editor that makes it easy to wire together flows using the wide range of nodes in the palette that can be deployed to its runtime in a single-click.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Going for a walk</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/going-for-a-walk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-21:/portfolio/going-for-a-walk.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the beautiful hills near Bern.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Cat approved</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/cat-approved.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-20:/portfolio/cat-approved.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows sunday is lazy day...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Sewing</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/sewing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-19:/portfolio/sewing.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made myself the softest dress in the world!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Spring</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/spring.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-18:/portfolio/spring.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is in the air&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Anxiety</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/anxiety.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-17:/portfolio/anxiety.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Exploring how to express anxiety felt relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Today I saw...</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/today-i-saw.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-16:/portfolio/today-i-saw.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This happy baby on the tram&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>Workshop Visualisieren</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/workshop-visualisieren.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sara Peeters</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2018-05-15:/portfolio/workshop-visualisieren.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aufzeichnungen einer Autistin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="diary"></category></entry><entry><title>8 Things you need to know about autism and bilingualism</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/8-things-you-need-to-know-about-autism-and-bilingualism.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Bérengère Digard</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2017-10-27:/portfolio/8-things-you-need-to-know-about-autism-and-bilingualism.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing several languages shapes the way people interact and the way they lead their social life. But how does it work for people on the autism spectrum, who can experience specific difficulties in social interaction? To answer this question, I designed the Autism &amp;amp; Bilingualism Census (ABC), an online survey addressed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Knowing several languages shapes the way people interact and the way they lead their social life. But how does it work for people on the autism spectrum, who can experience specific difficulties in social interaction? To answer this question, I designed the Autism &amp;amp; Bilingualism Census (ABC), an online survey addressed to all adults on the autism spectrum, monolinguals and multilinguals alike. By focusing on both the language exposure and use, and the general life satisfaction and social involvement of the participants, the ABC is new, unique, and valuable tool to understand how knowing several languages influences the way adults on the autism spectrum lead their social life. The ABC also brings to light this population often overlooked that are bilinguals and multilinguals on the autism spectrum. The ABC will be completed by the summer 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Lerne weitere germanische Sprachen mit Hilfe der historischen Linguistik</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/lerne-weitere-germanische-sprachen-mit-hilfe-der-historischen-linguistik.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ellen de Visser</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2017-10-27:/portfolio/lerne-weitere-germanische-sprachen-mit-hilfe-der-historischen-linguistik.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In diesem Vortrag nehme ich das Publikum mit auf eine Reise durch die Geschichte der germanischen Sprachen und erkläre das grimmsche Gesetz, wie eine Sprache sich durch die Zeit verändern kann und was die größten Faktoren dabei sind. Warum sagt jeder, dass Niederländisch eine Mischung aus Deutsch und Englisch sei …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In diesem Vortrag nehme ich das Publikum mit auf eine Reise durch die Geschichte der germanischen Sprachen und erkläre das grimmsche Gesetz, wie eine Sprache sich durch die Zeit verändern kann und was die größten Faktoren dabei sind. Warum sagt jeder, dass Niederländisch eine Mischung aus Deutsch und Englisch sei? Warum sind diese drei Sprachen so ähnlich und wie kann man leicht mit Hintergrundwissen dieser Sprachen neues Vokabular lernen? Und wie kommt es zum Gebrauch des ‚Denglischen‘? Am Ende des Vortrages werde ich die Lautverschiebungsgesetze mit dem Publikum üben und zeigen, wie leicht es ist, sein Vokabular bei diesen Sprachen zu erweitern. Ein Beispiel: wenn man weiß, dass das t zu einem s wird, weiß man, dass das niederländische ‚water‘ im Deutschen ‚Wasser‘ bedeutet. Wenn man sich diesen allgemeinen Regeln bewusst ist, kann man, schon wenn man anfängt eine dieser Sprachen zu lernen, beispielsweise schneller einen Text lesen und verstehen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Turkic Languages, Multilingualism and Polyglottery</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/turkic-languages-multilingualism-and-polyglottery.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Johan Vandewalle</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2017-10-27:/portfolio/turkic-languages-multilingualism-and-polyglottery.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Throughout the centuries, Turkic languages (41 in number according to Ethnologue) have been spoken over a vast, nearly continuous area, stretching out from the Balkans in the west to Siberia and the Chinese Wall in the east. Recently, the Turkish diaspora, with more than 4 million people of Turkish origin …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Throughout the centuries, Turkic languages (41 in number according to Ethnologue) have been spoken over a vast, nearly continuous area, stretching out from the Balkans in the west to Siberia and the Chinese Wall in the east. Recently, the Turkish diaspora, with more than 4 million people of Turkish origin in Western Europe, was added to this area. This broad dispersion of the Turkic languages has led to numerous multilingual situations, in which Turkic languages came into contact with genetically and typologically quite different language families: Indo-European (Slavic, Albanian, Greek, Iranian, Armenian), Semitic (Arabic), Sino-Tibetan, Mongolic and Tungusic. This contact often yielded linguistically fascinating results in both the Turkic and the non-Turkic languages. All of this makes turcology a very demanding study as to the required knowledge of languages by researchers. It is therefore not surprising that many of the well known turcologists are or have been polyglots. The aim of this talk is to give an overview of this huge variety of multilingual situations, demonstrating with clear examples the linguistic effects of the language contact and discussing the requirements as to the knowledge of foreign languages by researchers. Finally, a number of famous turcologists will pass in review and their knowledge of foreign languages will be described.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry><entry><title>Python, Locales and Writing Systems</title><link href="https://aspigirlcodes.github.io/portfolio/python-locales-and-writing-systems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Rae Knowler</name></author><id>tag:aspigirlcodes.github.io,2017-02-17:/portfolio/python-locales-and-writing-systems.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Python 3 removes a lot of the confusion around Unicode handling in Python, but that by no means fixes everything. Different locales and writing systems have unique behaviours that can trip you up. Here's some of the worst ones and how to handle them correctly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talks"></category></entry></feed>